hosting-marketers.com 2019-10-09

# Our Privacy Policy

## Our Privacy Policy

 **This Privacy Policy will be effective as of May 25, 2018 for all Hosting Marketers customers.**

We are strongly committed to safeguarding customers’ privacy. We operate under the following strict privacy policy:

## INFORMATION COVERED BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy policy covers personal information, including any information we collect, use and share from you, as described further below. This privacy policy applies to all websites hosted at Hosting Marketers servers, our products and services, and our mobile applications (collectively, the “Services”). This privacy policy does not cover how our Users may use or share data that they collect using our services.

When you purchase a Service from us, your personal information will be collected, used, and shared consistent with the provisions of this privacy policy.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU

In the course of your use of the Services, we obtain the following information about you as described below.

### SIGNING UP FOR SERVICES; USER INFORMATION

  * Information you provide prior to any registration process, such as your email when you provide it to us;
  * Information that you provide during any registration process, including in connection with a co-branded offer (such as your name, company name, email address, phone number, billing address or credit card information, geographic location and industry), when you call or email us (for support or otherwise) or when you use our products or services; and
  * Payment information that you provide to us (by way of our Services or otherwise) when you purchase some of our products and services, including credit card data.

### USE OF SERVICES, WEBSITE VISITS AND SUPPORT

  * Data relating to your online activity on our websites with respect to our Services, including the following:
    *       * IP address
      * browser type and version
      * geographic location
      * pages you view
      * how you got to our Services and any links you click on to leave our Services
      * when you update your information, communicate with us, or order new Services
      * metadata about your use and your contacts’ use of our Services and your emails you send (including clicks and opens)
      * issues you encounter requiring our support or assistance
      * any device or other method of communication you use to interact with the Services

We store this data we collect in a variety of places within our infrastructure, including system log files, back end databases and analytics systems.

  * Your telephone conversations with us (which we may monitor or record).

  * Information from third party social networking sites, including information that social networking sites provide to us if you use your credentials at such social networking sites to log into some of our Services (such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign-up form).
  * The information you allow us to access varies by social networking site, and depends on the level of privacy settings you have in place at the social networking site. You can control and find out more about these privacy settings at the applicable social networking site.

## HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We have a legitimate interest in running a successful and efficient business and in providing you with Services and useful content, and we use the information we collect, both on its own and combined with any other information we collect about you, for the following purposes:

  * To provide the requested Services to you;
  * To ensure the proper functioning of our Services
  * To offer and improve our Services;
  * To provide you with requested information or technical support
  * To facilitate your movement through our websites or your use of our Services;
  * To do a better job of advertising and marketing our Services (our use of your information to do this is performed with your consent where required by applicable law);
  * To advertise and market third party products and services (such advertisement is only performed with your permission where your consent is required by applicable law)
  * To diagnose problems with our servers or our Services;
  * In connection with our security and compliance programs;
  * To administer our websites;
  * To communicate with you;
  * To target prospective customers with our products or services (such targeting is only performed with your permission where your consent is required by applicable law);
  * To assist us in offering you a personalized experience or otherwise tailor our Services to you; and
  * As otherwise described in this privacy policy.

We also use the information we receive in aggregated and anonymized formats to produce reports on trends and statistics, such as mobile search trends, email open rates by industry, campaign best practices or the number of users that have been exposed to, or clicked on, our websites or evaluated or purchased our products and services.

Payment information that you provide to us, including credit card data, will only be used to facilitate payment for our products and services.

We also use recorded telephone conversations for quality control purposes, to train our employees and for our own protection.

## SHARING OF INFORMATION

As further described below, we will only share certain personal information with:

 **Domain Registration**. In certain jurisdictions or pursuant to the rules of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (“ICANN”) or certain registries, the contact information you provide to register a domain name (“Domain Name Registration Information”) has to be made available and accessible to the public through a “WHOIS” search. The WHOIS database is a publicly accessible database that lists the Domain Name Registration Information for a particular domain name, the name server(s) to which the domain name points, and the domain name’s creation and expiration date. The Domain Name Registration Information you provide is hosted by us or a third party service provider and is made available to the public through WHOIS searches. At times, customers may receive solicitations that result from searches of the publicly available WHOIS database by other companies or individuals. Any such solicitations or SPAM do not come from Hosting Marketers and we do not control the use of WHOIS information by third parties. Further, pursuant to ICANN rules, Hosting Marketers is required to make WHOIS data available to any third party that enters into a bulk access agreement. While ICANN allows individuals to opt-out (using the account management panel, domain management console or similar service) of having their WHOIS information made available to third parties through bulk access, companies, such as ours, businesses, and other organizations do not have the ability to opt-out of having their information made available to a third party that enters a bulk access agreement. We may also deposit your Domain Name Registration Information with a third-party escrow provider to comply with ICANN requirements.

 **Legal Reasons.** We may access, preserve and share information about customers with companies, organizations, governmental entities or individuals outside of Hosting Marketers if we believe, in good faith, that the law requires us to do so. This may include, but is not limited to, responding to subpoenas, court orders or other legal processes (such as law enforcement requests). We may also access, preserve and share information about customers as necessary to: (i) establish or exercise Hosting Marketers’s legal rights or defend against any legal claim including threatened claims involving Hosting Marketers based on the anonymity of a domain name; (ii) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected fraud or other illegal activities; (iii) prevent death or serious physical harm to any person; or (iv) investigate violations of Hosting Marketers’s Terms of Service.

## SECURITY

The transmission of information via the internet, email or text message is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted through the Services or over email; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will take appropriate technical and organizational measures to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft and unauthorized use, access or modification.

When we collect financial account information, such as credit card numbers, we protect its transmission through the use of encryption such as the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol.

## TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES AND ONLINE ADVERTISING

We use cookies, web beacons, pixels, tags, scripts and other similar technologies in the course of our business.

## CHOICE/OPT-OUT

### MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS FROM US

#### EMAIL

You always have the opportunity to opt out of our marketing communications with you or change your preferences by following a link in the footer of all non-transactional email messages from us or by emailing us at info@hosting-marketers.com. Some communications from us are considered transactional or service communications (for example, important account notifications and billing information), and your account(s) for Hosting Marketers products and services are provided to you upon the condition that you receive these communications from us. You must cancel your account(s) for Hosting Marketers products and services, as applicable, if you do not wish to receive any transactional or service communications. To cancel your Hosting Marketers account(s), login to our customer dashboard, select the service, click Manage and then click cancel. You may still receive marketing communications from us even after you cancel your account unless you also opt-out of our marketing communications, as described above.

If an account or profile was created without your knowledge or authorization, please contact customer support at the brand on which the account or profile is located to request removal of the account or profile.

## RETENTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We retain your personal information to provide services to you and as otherwise necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will retain your personal information for no more than seven years following the later of (i) the date on which you terminate your use of the Services or (ii) May 25, 2018, unless we are otherwise required by law or regulation to retain your personal information for longer.

## YOUR RIGHTS

Where the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679, or GDPR, applies, in certain circumstances and subject to data processing agreements, you have rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you. We set out below an outline of those rights and how to exercise those rights. Please note that we will require you to verify your identity before responding to any requests to exercise your rights by providing details only known to the account holder. To exercise any of your rights, please email info@hosting-marketers.com. Please note that for each of the rights below we may have valid legal reasons to refuse your request, in such instances we will let you know if that is the case.

### ACCESS

You have the right to know whether we process personal information about you, and if we do, to access data we hold about you and certain information about how we use it and who we share it with.

### PORTABILITY

You have the right to receive a subset of the personal information you provide us if we process it on the legal bases of our contract with you or with your consent in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and a right to request that we transfer such personal information to another party. If you wish for us to transfer the personal information to another party, please ensure you detail that party and note that we can only do so where it is technically feasible. We are not responsible for the security of the personal information or its processing once received by the third party.

### CORRECTION

You have the right to require us to correct any personal information held about you that is inaccurate and have incomplete data completed. Where you request correction, please explain in detail why you believe the personal information we hold about you to be inaccurate or incomplete so that we can assess whether a correction is required. Please note that while we assess whether the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you may exercise your right to restrict our processing of the applicable data as described below.

### ERASURE

You may request that we erase the personal information we hold about you in the following circumstances:

  * where you believe it is no longer necessary for us to hold the personal information;
  * we are processing it on the basis of your consent and you wish to withdraw your consent;
  * we are processing your data on the basis of our legitimate interest and you object to such processing;
  * you no longer wish us to use your data to send you marketing; or
  * you believe we are unlawfully processing your data.

Please provide as much detail as possible on your reasons for the request to assist us in determining whether you have a valid basis for erasure.

### RESTRICTION OF PROCESSING TO STORAGE ONLY

You have a right to require us to stop processing the personal information we hold about you other than for storage purposes in the following circumstances:

  * You believe the personal information is not accurate for the period it takes for us to verify whether the data is accurate;
  * We wish to erase the personal information as the processing we are doing is unlawful but you want us to simply restrict the use of that data;
  * We no longer need the personal information for the purposes of the processing but you require us to retain the data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; or
  * You have objected to us processing personal information we hold about you on the basis of our legitimate interest and you wish us to stop processing the personal information while we determine whether there is an overriding interest in us retaining such personal information.

### OBJECTION

You have the right to object to our processing of data about you and we will consider your request. Please provide us with detail as to your reasoning so that we can assess whether there is a compelling overriding interest in us continuing to process such data or we need to process it in relation to legal claims.

You also have the right, at any time, to object to our processing of data about you in order to send you marketing, including where we build profiles for such purposes and we will stop processing the data for that purpose.

### WITHDRAWAL OF CONSENT

Where you have provided your consent to us processing your personal data, you can withdraw your consent at any time by canceling your account and emailing us to delete your profile.

## THIRD PARTY LINKS AND INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE BY OUR USERS

Some of our Services provide links to other websites. Because we do not control the information policies or practices of these third party sites, you should review their privacy policies to learn about how they collect and use personal information.

You may also log in to some of our Services using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you with the option to share certain personal information with us, such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. For example, if you take advantage of certain of our social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, and widgets, such as the “Share This” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site, the applicable social networking sites may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our websites, and may set a cookie to enable it to function properly.

## CHILDREN

Our Services are not directed to persons under 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal information without such parent or guardian’s consent, he or she should contact us. If we become aware that a child under 18 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our files.

## DATA TRANSFER

In order for us to provide the Services to you, your personal information will be transferred to, and stored at/processed in the United States. Your personal data is also processed by staff operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA), such as in USA, India and the Philippines, who work for us or for one of our suppliers. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.

## COMPLAINTS

In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how we process your personal information, please contact us at info@hosting-marketers.com and we will try to deal with your request.

## NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. In all cases, your continued use of any Services constitutes acceptance to any such changes.

 **Last modified May 23, 2018**
